#### WAYNE LAMBERT

## Edgbaston, Birmingham, UK

contact@waynelambert.dev | +44 (0)7950 315504

Innovative Business Intelligence specialist and applications developer with over 15 years' experience managing the design, development, and delivery of effective, intuitive, and user-friendly solutions.

Engages clients and senior managers providing project updates and specialist product guidance. Enjoys collaborating in teams to transform business outcomes.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

**Programming:** Algorithms, data structures, design patterns, coding, debugging, testing, logging

Languages: Python, HTML / CSS, JavaScript, JSX, SQL, Unix shell scripting, VBA

Frameworks: Django, Django REST, Flask, React.js, Bootstrap, Ant

**Developer Tools:** VS Code, PyCharm, iTerm, GitHub, Docker, Firefox Dev Tools, DataGrip, Paw, Linux, AWS

**Databases / Other:** PostgreSQL, SQLite3, Oracle, SQL Server

#### **PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS**

- **Designed and developed comprehensive web portfolio:** Built using latest web technologies including Django, Django REST, Python, JavaScript, GitHub, Docker, Postgres, HTML / CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Developed tools contributing to saving an estimated €80m: Developed a comprehensive suite of VBA tools using an adaptation of Agile. Implemented fixed pay target ranges across cost base of €3.4bn, assignment of inbound team emails using operational logic, and delivered automated email communications to circa 40,000 employees.
- Augmented executive management compensation reporting with €2.1bn bonus pool: Facilitated global compensation strategy and policy for the Senior Executive Compensation Committee through interactive dashboard creation and key message insights.
- Managed workstream as part of large-scale HR transformation: Managed ETL data migration programme and redeveloped strategic reporting landscape installing Data Quality Management through BusinessObjects Web Intelligence. SME in recruitment, lifecycle, payroll, performance, reward, and organisational effectiveness.
- Improved reporting efficiency and key messages/insights reporting: Improved accuracy and reporting efficiency by transforming processes previously taking over 6 days to around 1 day. This was achieved through leadership in the development and streamlining of corporate MI dashboard reporting and the introduction of QA.

## **CAREER HISTORY**

## HR BI Specialist [Ltd Co Contractor] - Deutsche Bank, Birmingham

Nov 2016 - May 2019

- Designed and developed a salary ranges VBA tool enabling employee target ranges to be cost-contained.
- Developed Access / Excel VBA solutions automating assignment of team emails and sending of email broadcasts.
- Transformed interactive dashboards and key messages insights for global Senior Executive Compensation Committee.

# BI Developer & Data Migration Specialist [Ltd Co Contractor] - Admin Re UK, Telford, Shrops May 2016 - Nov 2016

- Managed comprehensive end-to-end data migration programme from existing HR administration and payroll
  providers onto single consolidated platform managing downstream system stakeholders and external consultants.
- Developed advanced VBA recruitment and data management solutions to effect robust data integrity, positive manager experiences, and streamlined operational efficiency.

### HR MIS Specialist [Ltd Co Contractor] - Deutsche Bank, Birmingham

Nov 2015 - May 2016

- Co-ordinated centralised data for approximately 91,000 employees to implement a global Total Compensation
   Framework. This included the allocation of mandatory, discretionary, promotion, and PayMix shift budgetary spend.
- Managed compensation planning and employee maintenance serving as data custodian, process owner, and stakeholder manager to divisional and regional reward advisors to enable management of employee populations.
- Created system to co-ordinate over 10,000 corrections making system updates and ensuring data integrity and audit requirements were adhered to.

- Created technical data feeds solution to automate downstream business systems supporting general ledgers, business modelling, and systems and facilities access.
- Developed inputs to a data warehousing solution enabling HR and Finance departments to align commercial analysis.
   Engagement of Strategic Change to introduce 'FTE Resource Tracker' as model owner, SME, and escalation point.
- Created a census "flight tracker" for business transformation, employee exit planning, and redundancy calculations.
- Facilitated change, project, and risk management through quality assurance and product/process reviews.

#### HR Systems & MI Consultant - TATA Consultancy Services, Peterborough, Cambs

Apr 2006 - Sep 2012

 Development and provision of MI reports as outsourced services provider for The Phoenix Group, Southern Water, and Sun Life Financial of Canada within a commercial operating environment governed by contractual SLAs and KPIs.

Roles prior to April 2006 include Stock Controller and Production Team Leader.

From 2010-2014, built and maintained an active WordPress membership website reaching a consistent Alexa rank of circa 60,000. This entailed blog and video content creation, PayPal eCommerce, AWeber email, Google Analytics, Linux and MySQL database administration, HTML / CSS modifications, Amazon S3 and CloudFront.

Consulted independently and delivered several freelance projects including designing a database schema for a Cultural Audit and Map for Dublin City Council.

#### **SKILLS PROFILE**

**Data Science:** Anaconda: Jupyter, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn

Business Intelligence: BusinessObjects, MS Excel, MS Access, dashboards, data visualisation, DQM, self-service BI

Project Management: Agile, stakeholder engagement, risk / change management, QA

Tools / Media: WordPress, SEO, AdWords, Google Analytics, Camtasia, split testing, online media

Systems / Other: MacOS, Windows, Linux, AutoCAD, iTrent, PeopleSoft, data warehousing, ETL data migration

#### **PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

Enjoys a continuous programme of self-study for professional and personal development principally targeted towards skills in software engineering, web development, data science, and business intelligence.

In addition to numerous video courses, I have studied many highly regarded books by industry leading experts in programming and web development. These include 'Clean Code', 'A Common-Sense Guide to Data Structures and Algorithms', 'Django for Professionals', 'REST APIs with Django', and 'Think Python'.

### **EDUCATION**

#### Robert Manning School (now Bourne Academy) - Bourne, Lincs

- GNVQ Advanced Business Studies
- 5 GCSEs at grades B C

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

My web development work can be reviewed on my portfolio website, <a href="https://waynelambert.dev">https://waynelambert.dev</a>, and its source code can be browsed using the 'View Code' button on the home page.

References available upon request